

My expertise lies in bridging the gap between design and implementation. I am passionate about understanding human behavior and designing for users. I specialize in software and hardware prototyping techniques. I am also a robotics researcher and a full-stack engineer.

EDUCATION

MS in Human Centered Design and Engineering

University of Washington, Seattle, WA | Sep 2015 - Mar 2017 (Expected)

B.Tech in Electronics and Communications Engineering

National Institute of Technology Karnataka, IN | Aug 2006 - May 2010

WORK EXPERIENCE

Student Researcher, Human-Centered Robotics Lab

University of Washington, Seattle, WA | Oct 2015 - Present

- > Research, design and evaluation of:
 - » Social and Conversational Robots for teaching English to children in rural Africa.
 - **» 3D Interfaces** for Robot Tele-Operation and Interactive Manipulation.

Student Assistant, Department of Urban Design and Planning

University of Washington, Seattle, WA | Oct 2015 - Present

- > Design and implementation of :
 - » Interactive mapping and visualization tools for visualizing land risks and natural hazards.
 - » MVP and functional prototypes for tools to increase understanding of natural hazards among current and future home-owners, real estate agents, insurers, and developers.

Full Stack Engineer + Designer, (Core Founding Team Member)

IIL Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore, IN | Apr 2012 - Sep 2015

- > Designed and developed multi-platform solutions for clients to improve marketing strategies and customer engagement for their products:
 - » Performed complete UCD lifecycle and led the implementation and deployment of solutions.
 - » Increased Customer Engagement by 3X and Sales Conversion from 7% to 25% in first month.
 - » Enabled timely and data-driven decisions, reducing reaction time from 1 week to few seconds.
- > Created MVPs, mock-ups, software and hardware prototypes for validating product ideas with potential users and for product demos to clients and investors.
- > Developed **product visions**, **marketing strategies** and **business models** for in-house products.

Technology Consultant, Research and Development

India Innovation Labs, Bangalore, India Jun 2010 - Sep 2015

- > Researched and developed Robotics, Computer Vision and Natural User Interface technologies
- > Collaborated with industry partners to research, develop and evaluate numerous software and hardware prototypes and applications for emerging technologies.
- Mentored 20+ undergraduate engineering students in Robotics and Computer Vision projects.

- > www.sahil-anand.com
- > syanand@uw.edu
- > (206) 954 8144

SKILLS

UX

User Research Usability Evaluations Wireframing Low to Hi-Fi Prototyping Interaction Design Data Analysis

User-Centered Design

Design Tools

Adobe Creative Suite Balsamiq **UXPin** Unity Autodesk Maya

Programming

C/C++

lava

Python

HTML, CSS

Javascript

Arduino

SparkCore

Raspberry Pi

Frameworks

OpenCV

ROS

Unity

NodeJS

AngularJS

Dojo

Meteor

Django